<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tyler Clavelle</title>
    <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tyler Clavelle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2016 Tyler Clavelle</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 18:39:07 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tclavelle.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy citations in RMarkdown with RefManageR</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/reference_tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 18:39:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/reference_tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s Monday (or at least it was when I started writing this), so what better way to make the week’s most boring day even more boring than to write about citations? Managing and formatting references for your research is, well, about as fun as it sounds. Fortunately, gone are the days of manually curating these lists and cut/pasting your way to an alphabetical bibliography. In this post, I’ll demonstrate how to use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/RefManageR/RefManageR.pdf&#34;&gt;RefManageR&lt;/a&gt; package to manage your references and easily automate citations and bibliographies in RMarkdown documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;using-a-reference-manager&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Using A Reference Manager&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zotero.org&#34;&gt;Zotero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://endnote.com&#34;&gt;EndNote&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mendeley.com&#34;&gt;Mendeley&lt;/a&gt; are all excellent reference managers, each with their own variety of browser plug-ins and desktop apps that make saving, searching, and inserting references &lt;em&gt;slightly&lt;/em&gt; more enjoyable. I personally use &lt;strong&gt;Zotero&lt;/strong&gt;. I have the Safari plug in that makes it easy to save references directly to my Zotero library from journal websites. The desktop app is a convenient way to browse the references and open up PDFs when needed, and it will also retrieve the metadata for a PDF you add to it, removing the need to enter that info yourself (author, year, journal, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/zotero_desktop.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All reference manager platforms should allow you to export your bibliography as a variety of file types, which can subsequently be used by RMarkdown (and LaTeX and most word processors) to insert citations and a bibliography in a consistent format. I’ll be talking about &lt;code&gt;.bib&lt;/code&gt; files, which is a style-independent text-based file format (essentially just a formatted list of your references), but the same process should work for other file types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;.bib&lt;/code&gt; files has numerous advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily switch between citation formats&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create and update bibliographies automatically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compatible across platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to share with coauthors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these benefits can take a bit of the sting out of adjusting your paper’s citations to the next journal as those rejection letters pile up. Using &lt;code&gt;.bib&lt;/code&gt; files in RMarkdown documents is really straight forward. Simply save the &lt;code&gt;.bib&lt;/code&gt; file in your directory of choice and then point to it in the front matter of your RMarkdown document:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
title: &amp;quot;Crazy awesome paper that&amp;#39;s definitely getting accepted&amp;quot;
output: html_document
bibliography: bibliography.bib
---&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;citations-in-rmarkdown&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Citations in RMarkdown&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re now ready to start inserting citations in our RMarkdown document by placing the reference id within square brackets and using the &lt;code&gt;@&lt;/code&gt; symbol, e.g, &lt;code&gt;[@costello16]&lt;/code&gt;. Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/authoring_bibliographies_and_citations.html&#34;&gt;RMarkdown documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more information on inserting citations using &lt;code&gt;.bib&lt;/code&gt; (or other) bibliography files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;citations-with-refmanager-and-zotero&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Citations with RefManageR and Zotero&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A disadvantage to using physical &lt;code&gt;.bib&lt;/code&gt; files is the need to update the &lt;code&gt;.bib&lt;/code&gt; file when you want to include new references. Fortunately, the &lt;code&gt;RefManageR&lt;/code&gt; package makes it easy for us to cut out the middle man. I’ll demonstrate how to use &lt;code&gt;RefManageR&lt;/code&gt; to interface with &lt;strong&gt;Zotero&lt;/strong&gt; directly to access our reference list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we’ll load the &lt;code&gt;tidyverse&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;RefManageR&lt;/code&gt; packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Packages
library(tidyverse)
library(RefManageR)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we need two pieces of information, the first of which is a Zotero &lt;code&gt;user&lt;/code&gt; id. Your Zotero user id can be found by logging in and navigating to &lt;code&gt;Settings &amp;gt; Feeds / API&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/zotero_id.png&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second required piece of information is a &lt;code&gt;collection&lt;/code&gt; id. Collections are another great thing about Zotero, allowing you to easily organize your references for each paper. They appear as sub-folders that you simply drag references to from &lt;em&gt;My Library&lt;/em&gt; (Zotero will not keep a copy in &lt;em&gt;My Library&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/zotero_web.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this example, we’ll link to my collection of articles about interactions between aquaculture (fish farming) and wild fisheries. The &lt;code&gt;collection&lt;/code&gt; id is just the last character set after &lt;code&gt;collectionKey/&lt;/code&gt; at the end of the collection’s URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;code&gt;user&lt;/code&gt; id and &lt;code&gt;collection&lt;/code&gt; id, we can connect to Zotero directly to get our reference information using the &lt;code&gt;ReadZotero()&lt;/code&gt; function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;biblio &amp;lt;- ReadZotero(user = &amp;lt;user_id&amp;gt;, .params = list(collection = &amp;#39;&amp;lt;collection_id&amp;gt;&amp;#39;))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ReadZotero()&lt;/code&gt; will return a list of references, which I’ve called &lt;code&gt;biblio&lt;/code&gt; here. At this point, we can start directly inserting citations in our RMarkdown document using &lt;code&gt;Cite()&lt;/code&gt; and providing the index for the reference in &lt;code&gt;biblio&lt;/code&gt; we want to cite. For example, &lt;code&gt;Cite(biblio[[1]])&lt;/code&gt; will insert a citation for the first reference in our reference list - (Sugimoto, San Diego-McGlone, Paciencia, Milan, Tomas, Ramírez, Echavez, Gabatin, Fortes, and Nadaoka, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ReadZotero()&lt;/code&gt; names each list index using an informative key string and we can make a look-up data frame with the reference titles and list element names to make indexing easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Find article keys to reference when in citations
refs &amp;lt;- biblio %&amp;gt;% {
  .$title
} %&amp;gt;%
  bind_rows() %&amp;gt;%
  gather(key = &amp;#39;key&amp;#39;, value = &amp;#39;title&amp;#39;, 1:19)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, each time we need to insert a citation we just look up its key in our &lt;code&gt;refs&lt;/code&gt; data frame and use it with &lt;code&gt;Cite(biblio[&#39;reference_key&#39;])&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;examples&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Examples&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China, Indonesia, India, Chile, Vietnam, and Myanmar are top-10 producers for both capture fisheries and aquaculture (FAO, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aquaculture regulations in numerous regions tend to be reactive, with many newcomers (e.g. Myanmar and Vietnam) promoting economic development at the expense of more restrictive policies like those imposed by incumbents, such as Thailand and the Philippines (Hishamunda, Ridler, Bueno, and Yap, 2009).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the absence of effective regulations, producers may adopt unsustainable practices that maximize their short-term profits but cause negative environmental and social damage that they are not held accountable for (Subasinghe, Soto, and Jia, 2009).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, when we’re all done writing, inserting a bibliography at the end of our paper is just one line of code using the &lt;code&gt;PrintBibliography(biblio)&lt;/code&gt; function embedded in a code chunk. Be sure to set the code chunk option &lt;code&gt;results = &#39;asis&#39;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] FAO, ed. &lt;em&gt;Contributing to food security and nutrition for all&lt;/em&gt;. Eng. The state of world fisheries and aquaculture 2016. OCLC: 957090850. Rome: Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, 2016. ISBN: 978-92-5-109185-2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] N. Hishamunda, N. B. Ridler, P. Bueno, et al. “Commercial aquaculture in Southeast Asia: Some policy lessons”. In: &lt;em&gt;Food Policy&lt;/em&gt;. Collective Action for Smallholder Market Access 34.1 (Feb. 2009), pp. 102-107. ISSN: 0306-9192. DOI: 10.1016/j.foodpol.2008.06.006. &amp;lt;URL: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0306919208000584&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0306919208000584&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt; (visited on 09/16/2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] R. Subasinghe, D. Soto and J. Jia. “Global aquaculture and its role in sustainable development”. En. In: &lt;em&gt;Reviews in Aquaculture&lt;/em&gt; 1.1 (Mar. 2009), pp. 2-9. ISSN: 1753-5131. DOI: 10.1111/j.1753-5131.2008.01002.x. &amp;lt;URL: &lt;a href=&#34;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1753-5131.2008.01002.x/abstract&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1753-5131.2008.01002.x/abstract&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt; (visited on 09/16/2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] A. Sugimoto, M. L. San Diego-McGlone, F. Paciencia, et al. “Comanagement for aquaculture: Suggestions from a comparative study between two major production areas of milkfish in the Philippines”. In: &lt;em&gt;Journal of Applied Aquaculture&lt;/em&gt; 28.4 (Oct. 2016), pp. 298-313. ISSN: 1045-4438. DOI: 10.1080/10454438.2016.1209712. &amp;lt;URL: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-tandfonline-com.proxy.library.ucsb.edu:2048/doi/full/10.1080/10454438.2016.1209712&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://www-tandfonline-com.proxy.library.ucsb.edu:2048/doi/full/10.1080/10454438.2016.1209712&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt; (visited on 02/15/2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it, we’re all setup and ready to start writing and citing our way to publication glory!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phish by the Numbers</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/phish_from_vt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 21:00:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/phish_from_vt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My geekiness is getting in the way of my nerdiness” - Patton Oswalt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phish is a quartet and stalwarts of the modern jam band scene they helped create in the late 80’s. Like their Deadhead contemporaries, Phish fans (phans) have an almost unhealthy obsession with the music, speaking in reverential tones of near mythical versions of songs, like 2015’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/jPrQYYlFPA4&#34;&gt;Tweezer -&amp;gt; Prince Caspian&lt;/a&gt;, while endlessly debating the details (for the record, no, I do not think they went back into Tweezer). This devotion to the music, an unabiding urge to get a taste of IT, has numerous implications - on bank accounts, relationships (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vogue.com/article/confessions-of-a-phish-wife&#34;&gt;Confessions of a Phish Wife&lt;/a&gt;), livers, and, in this case, data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coinciding with the emergence of the internet, phans have been compiling, debating, and analyzing Phish data online for literally decades. Whether it’s in the pursuit of tracking your “stats” (shows attended, songs heard, etc.) or quantifying “bust outs” (songs not heard in X many shows), data is no stranger to a Phish discussion. So, from the moment I learned that there are &lt;em&gt;numerous&lt;/em&gt; online sources of data about this band I love, the data monkey in my brain has been burning the banana at both ends thinking of ways to, like everything else in my life, over analyze Phish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;soundcheck&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Soundcheck&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data for this analysis comes from the following sources who are kind enough to make their data available through application programming interfaces (APIs):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://api.phish.net&#34;&gt;Phish.net&lt;/a&gt; - A project of the non-profit &lt;a href=&#34;http://mbird.org&#34;&gt;Mockingbird Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, an entirely volunteer run foundation started by Phish fans in 1996. If you enjoy this post, please consider making a donation!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://phish.in/api-docs&#34;&gt;Phish.in&lt;/a&gt; - A live Phish audio streaming site and my de facto homepage these days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.spotify.com/web-api/endpoint-reference/&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I access, analyze, and visualize all the data using &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;, an open source programming language original designed for statistical analyses but that can now make burritos, babysit your kid, and even moderate civil discussions between Trump supporters and Berkeley students. At least it seems that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve included certain interesting code blocks below but, for anyone interested in the full code, checkout my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tclavelle&#34;&gt;GitHub page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;set-1-the-band&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Set 1: The Band&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;where-does-phish-play&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Where does Phish play?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phish gained popularity the old fashioned way, by making the faces of New England college students melt harder than Nectar’s gravy fries while touring relentlessly in the late ’80s and early ’90s. By the mid ’90s, the Phish from Vermont had built a loyal fan base that, I would argue, remains one of music’s strongest to this day. Along the way, Phish played over hundreds of venues in almost every state. &lt;strong&gt;So, which states have Phish shown the most love over the years?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer this question, I used data on the number of shows per venue available &lt;a href=&#34;https://phish.net/venues&#34;&gt;here at phish.net&lt;/a&gt;. I couldn’t find an access point for this data through the .net API, so instead I chose to use the R package &lt;code&gt;rvest&lt;/code&gt; to scrape the data from the website itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Scrape table of show counts by venue from phish.net
url &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;https://phish.net/venues&amp;quot;
venues &amp;lt;- url %&amp;gt;%
  read_html() %&amp;gt;%
  html_nodes(xpath=&amp;#39;/html/body/div[1]/div[2]/table&amp;#39;) %&amp;gt;%
  html_table()
venues &amp;lt;- venues[[1]]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;xpath=&#39;/html/body/div[1]/div[2]/table&#39;&lt;/code&gt; argument refers to the table element on the page that I’m interested in. You can find this info by left-clicking and using the handy &lt;code&gt;Inspect&lt;/code&gt; feature in Chrome. For more about using &lt;code&gt;rvest&lt;/code&gt; to scrape data from the web, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.corynissen.com/2015/01/using-rvest-to-scrape-html-table.html&#34;&gt;this helpful post&lt;/a&gt; by Cory Nissen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Get data for state map
states &amp;lt;- map_data(map = &amp;#39;state&amp;#39;) 
state_info &amp;lt;- data_frame(region = state.name,
                         state      = state.abb)

# Summarize shows by state and join with map data
state_shows &amp;lt;- venues %&amp;gt;%
  tbl_df() %&amp;gt;%
  group_by(State) %&amp;gt;%
  summarize(shows  = sum(`Times Played`, na.rm = T),
            venues = length(`Venue Name`)) %&amp;gt;%
  rename(state = State) %&amp;gt;%
  left_join(state_info) %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(region  = tolower(region),
         percent = 100 * shows / sum(shows, na.rm = T)) %&amp;gt;%
  arrange(desc(shows))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I summarized the venue data to see how many shows and different venues Phish has played in each state (Figure 1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/phish_from_vt_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-5-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Map of Phish performances by State&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Map of Phish performances by State
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York (273 shows; 96 venues) and Vermont (259 shows; 68 venues) are the clear winners and collectively home to 532% of all Phish shows. California (115 shows; 55 venues), Colorado (111 shows; 83 venues), and Massachusetts (105 shows; 43 venues) are also no stranger to a Phish show. Wyoming, the Dakotas, and Arkansas…not so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-does-phish-play&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What does Phish play?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I always get a kick out of is watching the mental gymnastics people go through trying to comprehend how someone could see the same band multiple (13?) nights in a row, or 20, 40, 50, 100, 200+ times in their life. Some people get it, some people don’t, and when people don’t get it it’s almost as if you told them you pour milk in the bowl before the cereal. Utter madness. However, when the band your seeing has a catalog larger than Donald Trump’s supply of artificial tanner, every show is different. That being said, &lt;strong&gt;which songs do Phish play the most?&lt;/strong&gt; Again, I turned to &lt;strong&gt;phish.net&lt;/strong&gt; to find the number of performances of each song.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Get data from Phish.net
songs &amp;lt;- read_html(&amp;#39;http://phish.net/song/&amp;#39;)

# Get show table 
songs_df &amp;lt;- songs %&amp;gt;%
  html_nodes(&amp;#39;#song-list&amp;#39;) %&amp;gt;%
  html_table(fill = T)
songs_df &amp;lt;- songs_df[[1]]

# Prep data for wordcloud
songs_df &amp;lt;- songs_df %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(Times = as.numeric(Times),
         word  = as.factor(`Song Name`)) %&amp;gt;%
  rename(freq = Times) %&amp;gt;%
  select(word, freq) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(is.na(freq)==F &amp;amp; freq &amp;gt; 0)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a fan of using word clouds. I’m also a fan of the movie The Life Aquatic With Steve Zissou. So here’s a word cloud of the most played Phish songs using Steve Zissou’s favorite colors, courtesy of the wonderfully random &lt;code&gt;wesanderson&lt;/code&gt; R package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-7&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../img/phish_cloud.png&#34; alt=&#34;Word cloud of Phish songs sized by number of performances&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: Word cloud of Phish songs sized by number of performances
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, You Enjoy Myself, Phish’s pièce de résistance, is also their most performed song. Staples like Possum, Mike’s Song, Weekapaug Groove, Reba, Divided Sky, and Tweezer are also prominently displayed. Meanwhile, good luck finding Destiny Unbound in that thing. I guess even in nerd graphics she’s a rare beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a lifetime of music represented in the word cloud above, but simply playing the song is not what continues to attract middle-aged accountants, millennial unpaid interns, and your friendly neighborhood purveyor of heady crystals. It’s the jams. It’s when our favorite guitarist does his best impression of a constipated dentist patient while Mike hits you with the brown note that has kept us coming back and (mostly) speaking their praises for decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;set-2-the-jams&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Set 2: The Jams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, lists of noteworthy jams are carefully curated by the good folks at &lt;a href=&#34;http://phish.net/jamcharts&#34;&gt;Phish.net&lt;/a&gt;. These “jamcharts”, together with performance-specific data from &lt;strong&gt;phish.in&lt;/strong&gt; and Spotify, provide a cool opportunity to explore several questions about what makes a good Phish jam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;how-long-does-phish-jam&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How long does Phish jam?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s an extended psychedelic jam, a hard-hitting micro jam, or a unique rendition (&lt;a href=&#34;http://phish.in/1998-04-05/cavern&#34;&gt;4/5/1998 Cavern anyone?&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;em&gt;IT&lt;/em&gt; can happen at any time. That being said, Phish has deservedly earned a reputation for &lt;strong&gt;“playing the same song forever.” - annonymous Chad&lt;/strong&gt;. I think it’s a fair assumption that most phans crave that moment where Kuroda drops the lights and &lt;code&gt;[insert song here]&lt;/code&gt; melts into uncharted &lt;strong&gt;“Type 2”&lt;/strong&gt; territory. However, whether what emerges from the primal soup tickles your fancy more than when said song stays in it’s lane and smothers itself with extra mustard is, like, just your opinion man. With that said, let’s look at how the length of a song influences it’s chances of being admitted to the hallowed halls of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://phish.net/jamcharts&#34;&gt;Phish.net jamcharts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I extracted the jamcharts from Phish.net for a set of jam classics, including Tweezer, Bathtub Gin, David Bowie, and Down with Disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Get table of all jamcharts
jc_all &amp;lt;- GET(paste0(end_point,&amp;#39;jamcharts/all?apikey=&amp;#39;,api_key)) %&amp;gt;% content 
jc_all &amp;lt;- jc_all$response[2]$data

# Convert response to data frame
jc_all &amp;lt;- map_df(seq_len(length(jc_all)), function(x) {
  list(song = jc_all[[x]]$song,
       songid = jc_all[[x]]$songid,
       jams   = jc_all[[x]]$items)})

# Get info for top songs
top_jam_ids &amp;lt;- filter(jc_all, song %in% top_jams)

# Pull jamcharts for top_jam_ids
top_jams_charts &amp;lt;- lapply(top_jam_ids$songid, FUN = jam_chart) %&amp;gt;%
  bind_rows() %&amp;gt;%
  left_join(top_jam_ids)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I joined this data set of ear candy with data from the &lt;strong&gt;phish.in&lt;/strong&gt; API on song length and added labels for jamchart performances as well as for the coveted “Highly Recommended” jams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# join with Phish.in data on performances
jams &amp;lt;- top_songs %&amp;gt;%
  select(-slug) %&amp;gt;%
  left_join(top_jams_charts) %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(recommended = ifelse(is.na(highly_rec)==F, &amp;#39;Yes&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Sure&amp;#39;)) %&amp;gt;%
  distinct()

# add label for highly recommended jams
jams$recommended[jams$recommended == &amp;#39;Yes&amp;#39; &amp;amp; jams$highly_rec == 1] &amp;lt;- &amp;#39;Highly&amp;#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s look at what our complied data set shows us about the distribution of performances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-11&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/phish_from_vt_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-11-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Distributions of performance length and recommendation level&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 3: Distributions of performance length and recommendation level
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distinguishing type-1 and type-2 jams is more clear for certain songs than others. The clearest example is the dual peaks to the distribution for Ghost, where a version safely enters type-2 territory after 16 minutes. For other songs, like Bowie and Tweezer, the line between type-1 and type-2 is less clear, and for beloved classics like Reba and You Enjoy Myself you can usually count on surrendering to the flow for around 13 and 18 minutes, respectively (Table 1). Regardless, rest assured that, as each minute passed, you were increasingly likely to be witnessing something special. Also, don’t freak out if that Tweezer you were so stoked to catch bails out after only a few minutes, you may be in store for a highly recommended segue-fest. Lastly, if you witness the boys break the 30 minute mark, congratulations; don’t let your jaw break when it hit’s the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;caption&gt;
&lt;span id=&#34;tab:unnamed-chunk-12&#34;&gt;Table 1: &lt;/span&gt;Number of performances, average length, and standard deviation of popular Phish songs
&lt;/caption&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
Song
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
Performances
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
Average length
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
Standard deviation
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
Bathtub Gin
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
243
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
11.77
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
4.94
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
David Bowie
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
388
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
13.79
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
3.83
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
Down with Disease
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
267
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
12.84
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
5.24
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
Ghost
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
155
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
14.00
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
4.72
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
Mike’s Song
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
444
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
8.29
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
3.32
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
Reba
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
347
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
13.07
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
1.98
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
Tweezer
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
346
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
13.15
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
5.25
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
You Enjoy Myself
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
507
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
18.79
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;
4.50
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Figure 3 and Table 1 don’t show is how performances of these songs changed over time. This is an easy extension, and Figure 4 plots the average performance length of a song by year, with the number of performances indicated by dot size and the dotted line representing the overall average length of each song. The background colors indicate the different Phish “eras”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-13&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/phish_from_vt_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-13-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Average performance length by year&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 4: Average performance length by year
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’d be a lie to say the Mike’s Songs and David Bowie’s of today are as exploratory as they were in the ’90s. It’s not all bad news, however, as Down with Disease and Tweezer continue to regularly mix it up, while it would appear the band has really honed their groove in Reba, You Enjoy Myself, and Bathtub Gin over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;it-according-to-spotify&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;IT According to Spotify&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my final bit of Phish data nerdery (for now…) I decided to examine what Spotify can tell us about &lt;strong&gt;what makes a good Phish jam?&lt;/strong&gt; (if you haven’t already checked out Charlie Thompson’s excellent analysis, &lt;a href=&#34;http://rcharlie.com/2017-02-16-fitteR-happieR/&#34;&gt;Finding Radiohead’s most depressing song&lt;/a&gt;, I highly recommend you do so). All Spotify tracks receive scores for numerous metrics that, I assume, Spotify uses in their noble quest to help you discover new music (seriously, the Discover Weekly, Your Daily Mix, and Release Radar playlists are fantastic). These metrics include things such as &lt;code&gt;energy&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;danceability&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;instrumentalness&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;liveness&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;valence&lt;/code&gt; (how “happy” a song sounds), &lt;code&gt;key&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;tempo&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a first step, I extracted and plotted the key metrics for every live Phish song available from the Spotify API (Figure 5).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-15&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/phish_from_vt_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-15-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Spotify metrics for all Phish live performances available on Spotify&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 5: Spotify metrics for all Phish live performances available on Spotify
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I don’t work for Spotify and don’t know how they score these things, but when I see &lt;code&gt;instrumentalness&lt;/code&gt; as the lowest scoring metric I immediately think alternative-facts. According to the documentation, which you can read &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.spotify.com/web-api/get-audio-features/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you’re curious, &lt;code&gt;instrumentalness&lt;/code&gt; scores are more of a measure of the presence of vocals and not instrumental prowess. Why they didn’t go with a name like, oh I don’t know, &lt;strong&gt;vocals&lt;/strong&gt; is a bit of a mystery. You may also be wondering why I chose to include &lt;code&gt;liveness&lt;/code&gt; considering all the tracks are, well, live. The &lt;code&gt;liveness&lt;/code&gt; metric measures the presence of an audience in a track, which I decided could be a good way to gauge audience reaction to a jam. This likely has problems for set-opening and closing tracks, but oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, &lt;code&gt;instrumentalness&lt;/code&gt; rant aside, the rest of the scores generally make sense to me - high &lt;code&gt;energy&lt;/code&gt;, below average &lt;code&gt;danceability&lt;/code&gt; (unless you’re dancing style is classic white dude like mine), high audience engagement, and songs that take you on a trip across the entire range of emotions (&lt;code&gt;valence&lt;/code&gt;). These patterns also seem to be generally consistent across different songs (Figure 6).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-16&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/phish_from_vt_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-16-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Spotify metrics for all performances available of select Phish songs&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 6: Spotify metrics for all performances available of select Phish songs
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, we can combine Spotify’s track metrics with our previous data set of jamchart versions of songs to create a data set with which to ask the question &lt;strong&gt;what makes a good Phish jam?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer -&lt;/strong&gt; I’ll preface this by saying the following analysis is more meaningless than truth and integrity are to Paul Ryan. This data monkey Phish phan knows that no amount of number crunching can capture what makes a particular jam special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to flag all Spotify songs that are deemed &lt;em&gt;Highly Recommended&lt;/em&gt;, which is made easy thanks to the awesome Spotify playlist &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/user/1265043326/playlist/3FdZNyZ42vMB5szof9EA3N&#34;&gt;Phish.net “Highly Recommended”&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re a Phish phan and a Spotify user, good luck listening to anything else for the next three months. Again using the Spotify API, I extracted the track list of all “Highly Recommended” songs. I then added a binary variable to the complete data set of Spotify metrics labeling these versions with a 1 and all others with a 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I constructed a series of binary logistic regression models, which can be used in situations where the observed outcome can have only two possible outcomes, in this case “Highly Recommended” (1) or not (0).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of all three models are included below in Table 2, and they make me very happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34;border-bottom: 1px solid black&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Dependent variable:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&#34;3&#34; style=&#34;border-bottom: 1px solid black&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
highly_rec
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(1)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(2)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(3)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34;border-bottom: 1px solid black&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
instrumentalness
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
2.076&lt;sup&gt;***&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
2.060&lt;sup&gt;***&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
2.081&lt;sup&gt;***&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.292)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.291)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.290)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
energy
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-0.746
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-0.717
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-0.709
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.589)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.587)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.587)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
valence
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
1.180&lt;sup&gt;**&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
1.212&lt;sup&gt;**&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
1.230&lt;sup&gt;**&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.555)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.552)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.551)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
minutes
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
0.139&lt;sup&gt;***&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
0.137&lt;sup&gt;***&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
0.136&lt;sup&gt;***&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.017)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.017)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.017)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
liveness
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-1.578&lt;sup&gt;***&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-1.577&lt;sup&gt;***&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-1.579&lt;sup&gt;***&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.337)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.337)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.337)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
danceability
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-0.851
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-0.912
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-0.913
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(1.001)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.996)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.994)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
key
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
0.028
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
0.028
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.028)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.028)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
tempo
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
0.003
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.004)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
Constant
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-3.105&lt;sup&gt;***&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-2.792&lt;sup&gt;***&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-2.657&lt;sup&gt;***&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.781)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.638)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
(0.623)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34;border-bottom: 1px solid black&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
Observations
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
1,251
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
1,251
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
1,251
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
Log Likelihood
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-411.375
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-411.622
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
-412.136
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
Akaike Inf. Crit.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
840.750
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
839.244
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
838.273
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34;border-bottom: 1px solid black&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&#34;3&#34; style=&#34;text-align:right&#34;&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;p&amp;lt;0.1; &lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;p&amp;lt;0.05; &lt;sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;p&amp;lt;0.01
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what makes a good Phish jam? Well, according to Spotify, it’s when the Phish from Vermont take a song for an extended and highly instrumental journey. The results also suggest that positive “bliss” jams put a smile on your face for a reason. This is not to say that the dark and nasty grooves don’t get any love, just ask the &lt;a href=&#34;http://phish.in/2016-09-02/no-men-in-no-mans-land&#34;&gt;Dick’s No Men In No Man’s Land&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;energy&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;danceability&lt;/code&gt; of a song don’t preclude it from becoming “Highly Recommended”, which should make the lovers of spacey jams happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, there you have it, my data nerdery is finished getting in the way of my Phish geekery. If you’re a data person and have questions about my methods or code, let me know. If you’re a Phish phan, I hope you didn’t find this to be too sacrilegious. Either way, let me know what you think in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll end by saying that I strongly believe you can’t capture IT in a statistic. Besides, my license plate is currently duck-taped to the bumper of my station wagon, so you probably shouldn’t listen to me anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;encore&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Encore&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;encore &amp;lt;- as.character(0)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Blog with Blogdown and GitHub</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/blogdown_github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 16:17:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/blogdown_github/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started learning to code in R, Google was (and still is) my go-to when I had a question. It didn’t take long to realize that this generally brought me to one of two destinations - StackOverflow or [Insert Name]’s Blog. So, I created a StackOverflow account and decided to start my own data science blog. However, I didn’t quite know where to start and spent most of 2016 scoping different platforms. While I won’t go into all the details of this process, the cliff notes are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tried Jekyll. The installation and dependencies (e.g. Ruby) were more complicated than I wanted and I was hoping for a more direct integration of R into the workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a website with RMarkdown. Getting setup was a breeze but found the blogging capability to be lacking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rstudio/blogdown&#34;&gt;blogdown&lt;/a&gt;, the new brainchild of Yihui Xi. Though still in the early beta stage, blogdown checked all the boxes I was looking for. So, now that i’m up and running, it felt only natural to write my first blog post about how to get started blogging with &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rstudio/blogdown&#34;&gt;Blogdown&lt;/a&gt; is a R package that combines the ease of &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&#34;&gt;RMarkdown&lt;/a&gt; with the flexibility and customizability of &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. Hugo is an open-source static site generator similar to Jekyll, which means it builds your website once rather than each time a user visits it by taking all files within the website’s directory and rendering a complete website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;hosting-your-blog-with-github&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hosting Your Blog With GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I jump in to explaining how to use &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;, I want to first explain my approach to hosting my blog on GitHub, as it is important for the remainder of this post. User pages on GitHub require all site content (and only site content) to be on the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch. This is problematic for &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; sites because when Hugo builds your website it places the site content in a new folder called &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt;. Thus, your blog’s source and site content will be on the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch and GitHub will be unable to render your site. So far I’ve seen two options for getting around this issue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two branches (and a subbranch) -&lt;/strong&gt; Remove all source content from the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch and place it in a new branch, using a &lt;code&gt;subbranch&lt;/code&gt; to mirror the &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; folder on the new branch to the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch. While this method allows you to store all your content in the same repo, it’s rather confusing to set up if you’re not a GitHub ninja.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two repositories -&lt;/strong&gt; Create a repo to store your source content and tell &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; to publish the site to your &lt;code&gt;username.github.io&lt;/code&gt; repository each time you build your site. Though this approach is less streamlined than the two-branch method, the only real added hassle is remembering to push an additional repository to GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After initial partly-successful attempts to use the two-branch method, I decided to keep it simple and use the two repository method for my site. If you decide to go the two-branch route, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://proquestionasker.github.io/blog/Making_Site/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; great post by Amber Thomas (which was my primary resource) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/deploying-hugo-on-personal-gh-pages/index.html&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post by Jente Hidskes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;creating-your-blog&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Creating Your Blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, now that we’ve decided to use the two repository method to host our site, let’s get started making a blog with &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;create-a-github-repository&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Create a GitHub Repository&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, create a new repository for your blogdown source content. Initialize the repository with a &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/create_repo.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, click the green &lt;code&gt;clone or download&lt;/code&gt; button on the right side of your new repo’s page and copy the URL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/clone_repo.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open up Terminal and use &lt;code&gt;cd &amp;lt;desired directory&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to navigate to the directory where you’d like your new repository to live. I keep all my repos in a &lt;code&gt;GitHub/&lt;/code&gt; folder on my desktop, so I’ll put the repository there. After navigating to the desired directory, run &lt;code&gt;git clone &amp;lt;GitHub URL&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to clone the new repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/terminal_clone.png&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open up &lt;em&gt;Finder&lt;/em&gt;; you should now see the &lt;code&gt;blogdown_source/&lt;/code&gt; folder containing only the &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt; file. Now that you’ve successfully cloned the repo, delete the &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt; file. Don’t add anything else to this folder just yet, &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; requires an empty directory to get started.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you don’t already have a repository setup for your &lt;strong&gt;&lt;username&gt;.github.io&lt;/strong&gt; page, repeat steps 1-3 above and create that repo now as well. Later on in the setup process we’ll tell Hugo to publish our new site to this directory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;installing-hugo&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installing Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great feature of &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; is that it handles the installation of Hugo for you, which means you don’t need to know much about Hugo to start blogging with &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;. I found this to be a big advantage over the complicated dependencies and installation process of Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load the &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; package and run the &lt;code&gt;install_hugo()&lt;/code&gt; command. This can just be done in the console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Load blogdown package and install Hugo
library(blogdown)
install_hugo()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn’t get much more straight forward than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;build-your-site-with-blogdown&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Build Your Site with Blogdown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;code&gt;install_hugo()&lt;/code&gt;, blogdown provides the handy &lt;code&gt;new_site()&lt;/code&gt; function to automatically create the required structure for you website in the (empty) directory you specify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another great feature of this function is that you can use the &lt;code&gt;theme&lt;/code&gt; argument to specify the theme you want for your website and &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; will download all necessary files into the new site directory it creates. Check out Hugo’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io&#34;&gt;theme&lt;/a&gt; gallery for a ton of options. Let’s try the &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-tranquilpeak-theme/&#34;&gt;Tranquilpeak theme&lt;/a&gt; theme, which we specify with &lt;code&gt;theme = &#39;kakawait/hugo-tranquilpeak-theme&#39;&lt;/code&gt;, which is just the GitHub user and repo name for the theme. We’ll also set the &lt;code&gt;format&lt;/code&gt; argument to &lt;code&gt;format = &#39;toml&#39;&lt;/code&gt; to tell &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; that we want to use &lt;strong&gt;toml&lt;/strong&gt; for our site’s &lt;code&gt;config&lt;/code&gt; file. &lt;code&gt;toml&lt;/code&gt; is actually the default setting but I wanted to point it out because the &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; is important for customizing your website. Once you select a theme for your site, checkout the GitHub repo for the theme and determine whether the &lt;code&gt;theme&lt;/code&gt; file is a &lt;code&gt;.toml&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file and set the &lt;code&gt;format&lt;/code&gt; argument accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Create new site in our recently cloned blogdown repository
new_site(dir = &amp;#39;blogdown_source&amp;#39;, 
         theme = &amp;#39;kakawait/hugo-tranquilpeak-theme&amp;#39;,
         format = &amp;#39;toml&amp;#39;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few things happen upon running the above code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; will add all the required Hugo components to the previously empty directory, displaying the progress in your R console&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An example RMarkdown &lt;code&gt;post&lt;/code&gt; will be created and opened automatically&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;RStudio will start serving your site in the RStudio viewer, which you can open in your web browser by clicking on the arrow button next to the broom&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/new_site_serve.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations! You now have a functioning website created with &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;! However, before you’re ready to publish your site and start and writing blog posts, let’s first understand a bit more about how Hugo and &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; work together to organize and build your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;site-structure&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Site Structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open up your repository folder. You should see a bunch of new folders and files, including for the theme you told &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; to use for your website and the demo RMarkdown post in the &lt;code&gt;blogdown/post/&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/repo_structure.png&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you should definitely see &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/overview/source-directory/&#34;&gt;Hugo’s documentation&lt;/a&gt; for details on the purpose of these directories, I’ll explain the key elements you need to understand to get started with &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/overview/configuration/&#34;&gt;config.toml&lt;/a&gt; - The configuration file for your website. This file tells Hugo how it should render your site, as well as define its menus, and set various other site-wide parameters. This file will look different for every theme, but they will all contain some basic components.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;baseurl&lt;/code&gt; set this to the desired URL for your site, in this case &lt;code&gt;baseurl = &amp;quot;https://&amp;lt;usernamr&amp;gt;.github.io/&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; set the title for your new site. Some completely random and objective examples include “Real Leaks, Fake News”, “Gravy Fries and Putin”, and “Kellyanne’s Alternative Factory”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;description&lt;/code&gt; a brief description or mission of your new site, something like “Democracy Described in Data” or “Hair and Imbalanced”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;theme&lt;/code&gt; this should list the theme you specified when creating the site&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;publishDir&lt;/code&gt; tell &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; which directory it should place the rendered site in. This directory will include a copy of everything that gets generated in the &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; directory of your site’s root directory. To use the &lt;strong&gt;two repository&lt;/strong&gt; method described above, set this to &lt;code&gt;publishDir = &amp;quot;../&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.github.io&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;. Adjust this path to where ever you keep your &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.github.io&lt;/code&gt; repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; - The directory where Hugo will place your rendered website content. The contents of the &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; directory are the only things that can be present on the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch of your &lt;em&gt;username.github.io&lt;/em&gt; page in order for GitHub to render the site properly. This creates the need to use the &lt;strong&gt;two branch&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;two repository&lt;/strong&gt; approaches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/themes/overview/&#34;&gt;themes/&lt;/a&gt; - User generated themes powered by the Go template library. You should see a folder with the name of the theme you chose previously
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/templates/overview/&#34;&gt;themes/layout/&lt;/a&gt; - HTML templates that the Hugo theme uses to structure the layout of each page on your website. There are three primary layout types - &lt;strong&gt;single&lt;/strong&gt; (for single-content pages), &lt;strong&gt;list&lt;/strong&gt; (for pages with multiple pieces of content), and &lt;strong&gt;homepage&lt;/strong&gt; (any guesses?). Checkout this &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/templates/go-templates/&#34;&gt;Hugo documentation&lt;/a&gt; for an intro to using and creating these layout templates&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content/organization/&#34;&gt;content/&lt;/a&gt; - The main directory where your blog’s content will live. Each page of your site should exist as a sub directory of &lt;code&gt;content/&lt;/code&gt;. Each sub directory will consist of either a single &lt;code&gt;index.md&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt;) file, or a series of files representing multiple posts of the same content type&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;creating-new-content&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Creating New Content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, at this point we have a functioning Hugo website with a cool theme. We’ve set the &lt;code&gt;baseurl&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;publishDir&lt;/code&gt; and given our site a &lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;description&lt;/code&gt;. Now it’s time to start creating content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; lets you easily create new content with the aptly named &lt;code&gt;new_post()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;new_content()&lt;/code&gt; functions. These functions will both create a new RMarkdown or markdown file in a sub directory of &lt;code&gt;content/&lt;/code&gt; that you specify. &lt;code&gt;new_post()&lt;/code&gt; is essentially just a shortcut for &lt;code&gt;new_content(path = &#39;post/&#39;)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s create a new post, being sure not to include spaces or other special characters in out title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Create a new post
new_post(title = &amp;#39;hello-world.Rmd&amp;#39;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; helps us out by creating and opening the &lt;code&gt;.Rmd&lt;/code&gt; file for our new post, which it placed in the &lt;code&gt;content/post/&lt;/code&gt; directory. We could’ve specified &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; as the file type if we wanted to use plain markdown. The newly created file has &lt;code&gt;.yaml&lt;/code&gt; front matter, which includes the &lt;code&gt;date:&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;draft:&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;title:&lt;/code&gt; fields. Another thing &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; does is to prepend the date to the file name and title. This is done to assist with &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/content/ordering/&#34;&gt;ordering content&lt;/a&gt;, but we can remove the date from the &lt;code&gt;title:&lt;/code&gt; field as long as we keep the date in the file name and &lt;code&gt;date:&lt;/code&gt; field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/new_post.png&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now type away like any other RMarkdown document! When the site is rendered with &lt;code&gt;serve_site()&lt;/code&gt; the new &lt;code&gt;hello-world&lt;/code&gt; post will be the top entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/site_serve.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;publishing-your-new-site-to-github&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Publishing Your New Site to GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you’re creating this website for your eyes only, you still need to push it to GitHub before the rest of the world can read your tremendous blog entries. Don’t worry, GitHub and RStudio have some of the best people, great people, and publishing your new site is easier than, like, anything you’ve ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you either already have, or recently created, your &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;username.github.io&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; repository and cloned it to your local machine. You also already told Hugo to publish your site to this same repository using the &lt;code&gt;publishDir = &amp;quot;&amp;lt;username.github.io&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; option in your site’s &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; file. There’s only a few steps left!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tell Hugo to build your site with &lt;code&gt;build_site()&lt;/code&gt; (no arguments required). Once Hugo finishes rendering your site, take a look at your &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.gihub.io&lt;/code&gt; directory, it should now contain the same files as the &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; directory of your source content repository.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open up Terminal, navigate to your &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.gihub.io&lt;/code&gt; directory using &lt;code&gt;cd &amp;lt;path to username.github.io  repo&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Stage all changed files, commit your changes, and push your new site to GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it! Navigate to your new website &lt;code&gt;https://&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.github.io&lt;/code&gt; and check out your hard work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 18:32:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I finally did it. I started a blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a variety of reasons for venturing into the blogosphere. First, I like to tell stories. Writing these stories down is a good exercise because, in verbal form, my stories have a tendency to meander off on unforeseen (though completely necessary) tangents. Second, blogs have become a go-to for me when seeking answers to my programming-related questions so I decided to start contributing to this resource base. Finally, some really cool and innovative stories are being told via blog posts by data scientists these days. Check out David Robinson’s great piece that analyzed &lt;a href=&#34;http://varianceexplained.org/r/trump-tweets/&#34;&gt;Trump’s tweets&lt;/a&gt; and confirmed that Trump writes only the (angrier) Android half. In another cool post, Charlie Thompson recently used data from Spotify and Genius Lyrics to find &lt;a href=&#34;http://rcharlie.com/2017-02-16-fitteR-happieR/&#34;&gt;Radiohead’s most depressing song&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the ubiquity of data in our everyday lives, telling creative and data-driven stories is increasingly possible. With the strange political (and literal) climate situation, people are looking for ways to speak out or, occasionally, tune out. So, while it’s too early to say if this blog will follow a consistent theme, expect semi-quantitative ramblings on the environment, coding (particularly R), politics, beer, and music. Lots of music.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get in touch</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 13:00:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About Me&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tyler-clavelle-mesm&#34;&gt;Tyler Clavelle, MESM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;GitHub: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tclavelle&#34;&gt;tclavelle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Email: tclavelle@bren.ucsb.edu&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bren School of Environmental Science &amp;amp; Management&lt;/strong&gt; – University of California, Santa Barbara (UCSB)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Master of Environmental Science and Management (MESM)&lt;/strong&gt; | June 2014&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Coastal Marine Resources Management Specialization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bucknell University&lt;/strong&gt; – Lewisburg, PA&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Bachelor of Arts with a double major in Economics and Biology&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;cum laude&lt;/em&gt; | May 2009&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;publications&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Costello, C., Ovando, D., Clavelle, T., Strauss, C. K., Hilborn, R., Melnychuk, M. C., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Rader, D. N. (2016). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pnas.org/content/113/18/5125.abstract&#34;&gt;Global fishery prospects under contrasting management regimes.&lt;/a&gt; Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 201520420.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Melnychuk, M. C., Clavelle, T., Owashi, B &amp;amp; Strauss, C. K. (2016). &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com//icesjms/article/74/1/121/2670314/Reconstruction-of-global-exvessel-prices-of-fished?guestAccessKey=7f3cdd83-47fc-4a29-9466-2f8f5941a0e6&#34;&gt;Re-construction of global ex-vessel prices of fished species.&lt;/a&gt; ICES Journal of Marine Science. doi: 10.1093/icesjms/fsw169.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;experience&#34;&gt;Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainable Fisheries Group (SFG)&lt;/strong&gt; | Santa Barbara, CA | June 2013 - Present&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Project Researcher&lt;/strong&gt; | July 2014 – Present&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serving as a multidisciplinary researcher, performing quantitative analyses and collaborating on academic
publications and applied reports for external conservation organizations&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the R programming language to build and analyze environmental and economic datasets, conduct data-poor
stock assessments, and model alternative policy options&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building interactive web applications and automated reports for publishing and disseminating project
results&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actively engaged in numerous areas of fishery science, including data limited stock assessments,
interactions with aquaculture, spatial modeling, and bioeconomic forecasting&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducted a year-long scoping project of sustainable aquaculture, securing $100,000 in research funding
to examine environmental and economic tradeoffs between aquaculture and wild fisheries&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Co-authored a global analysis examining the current biological status, optimal harvest trajectories, and
economic potential of recovering the world’s fisheries&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Led a two day fishery workshop in the Philippines that convened local fishery scientists, government
officials, and NGO partners to inform a modeling analysis of Filipino fisheries&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborating with Google, Oceana, and SkyTruth on the Global Fishing Watch platform to use big data
techniques to investigate global industrial fishing effort&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ecosystem Service Valuation Intern&lt;/strong&gt; | The Bahamas | June 2013 – December 2013&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducted an economic valuation of marine ecosystem services in support of the successful declaration
of two marine protected areas (MPAs) in The Bahamas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used GIS to identify, map, and quantify the areas of five marine habitat types within proposed
boundaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interviewed local stakeholders and policy makers regarding their use and opinions of MPAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Produced a policy-relevant report presenting the valuation results and discussing the relative ecological
and economic significance of the proposed protected areas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Served as a reviewer and contributed on-the-ground feedback for the World Resources Institute’s Coastal
Capital: Ecosystem Valuation for Decision Making in the Caribbean guidebook&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bimini Biological Field Station (BBFS)&lt;/strong&gt; | The Bahamas | January 2010 – November 2011&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Assistant Manager&lt;/strong&gt; | June 2010 – November 2011&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helped plan, organize, and supervise daily fieldwork operations of a remote shark research facility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trained and supervised 70+ field assistants and 100+ university students in marine field research
techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guided daily tours educating the public on BBFS research and the importance of marine stewardship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisted logistical planning and on-site operations for a 10-day research cruise aboard a NOAA vessel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed, updated, and improved the BBFS website&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marine Research Intern&lt;/strong&gt; | January 2010 – June 2010&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducted field work (50 hours per week) for a project evaluating the effects of nursery habitat loss on
juvenile lemon sharks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;skills-certifications-and-affiliations&#34;&gt;Skills, Certifications &amp;amp; and Affiliations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computer Skills:&lt;/strong&gt; R/RStudio, git, GitHub, Shiny application development, Google Earth Engine, JavaScript,
SQL, GIS&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Certifications:&lt;/strong&gt; PADI Advanced SCUBA certified with 100+ dives&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Conferences:&lt;/strong&gt; 2015 SeaWeb Seafood Summit, New Orleans, LA; Aquaculture 2015: Cutting Edge Science in
Aquaculture, Montpelier, France; 2016 Google Earth Engine User Summit, Mountainview, CA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Name of the work 1</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even the all-powerful Pointing has no control about the blind texts it is an almost unorthographic life. One day however a small line of blind text by the name of Lorem Ipsum decided to leave for the far World of Grammar.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove right at the coast of the Semantics, a large language ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small river named Duden flows by their place and supplies it with the necessary regelialia. It is a paradisematic country, in which roasted parts of sentences fly into your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;header-level-2&#34;&gt;Header Level 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the all-powerful Pointing has no control about the blind texts it is an almost unorthographic life One day however a small line of blind text by the name of Lorem Ipsum decided to leave for the far World of Grammar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a last view back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of Alphabet Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane. Pityful a rethoric question ran over her cheek, then&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Name of the work 2</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a last view back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of Alphabet Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove right at the coast of the Semantics, a large language ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small river named Duden flows by their place and supplies it with the necessary regelialia. It is a paradisematic country, in which roasted parts of sentences fly into your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;header-level-2&#34;&gt;Header Level 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the all-powerful Pointing has no control about the blind texts it is an almost unorthographic life One day however a small line of blind text by the name of Lorem Ipsum decided to leave for the far World of Grammar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a last view back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of Alphabet Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane. Pityful a rethoric question ran over her cheek, then&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Name of the work 3</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:44:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fifth abundantly made Give sixth hath. Cattle creature i be don&amp;rsquo;t them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove right at the coast of the Semantics, a large language ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small river named Duden flows by their place and supplies it with the necessary regelialia. It is a paradisematic country, in which roasted parts of sentences fly into your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;header-level-2&#34;&gt;Header Level 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the all-powerful Pointing has no control about the blind texts it is an almost unorthographic life One day however a small line of blind text by the name of Lorem Ipsum decided to leave for the far World of Grammar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a last view back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of Alphabet Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane. Pityful a rethoric question ran over her cheek, then&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Item without image</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:50:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and Consonantia, there live the blind texts. A small river named Duden flows by their place and supplies it with the necessary regelialia. It is a paradisematic country, in which roasted parts of sentences fly into your mouth.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove right at the coast of the Semantics, a large language ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small river named Duden flows by their place and supplies it with the necessary regelialia. It is a paradisematic country, in which roasted parts of sentences fly into your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;header-level-2&#34;&gt;Header Level 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the all-powerful Pointing has no control about the blind texts it is an almost unorthographic life One day however a small line of blind text by the name of Lorem Ipsum decided to leave for the far World of Grammar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a last view back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of Alphabet Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane. Pityful a rethoric question ran over her cheek, then&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Name of the work 5</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:53:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fifth abundantly made Give sixth hath. Cattle creature i be don&amp;rsquo;t them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove right at the coast of the Semantics, a large language ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small river named Duden flows by their place and supplies it with the necessary regelialia. It is a paradisematic country, in which roasted parts of sentences fly into your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;header-level-2&#34;&gt;Header Level 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the all-powerful Pointing has no control about the blind texts it is an almost unorthographic life One day however a small line of blind text by the name of Lorem Ipsum decided to leave for the far World of Grammar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a last view back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of Alphabet Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane. Pityful a rethoric question ran over her cheek, then&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Name of the work 6</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:56:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fifth abundantly made Give sixth hath. Cattle creature i be don&amp;rsquo;t them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove right at the coast of the Semantics, a large language ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small river named Duden flows by their place and supplies it with the necessary regelialia. It is a paradisematic country, in which roasted parts of sentences fly into your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;header-level-2&#34;&gt;Header Level 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the all-powerful Pointing has no control about the blind texts it is an almost unorthographic life One day however a small line of blind text by the name of Lorem Ipsum decided to leave for the far World of Grammar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a last view back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of Alphabet Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane. Pityful a rethoric question ran over her cheek, then&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Name of the work 7</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:57:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fifth abundantly made Give sixth hath. Cattle creature i be don&amp;rsquo;t them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove right at the coast of the Semantics, a large language ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small river named Duden flows by their place and supplies it with the necessary regelialia. It is a paradisematic country, in which roasted parts of sentences fly into your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;header-level-2&#34;&gt;Header Level 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the all-powerful Pointing has no control about the blind texts it is an almost unorthographic life One day however a small line of blind text by the name of Lorem Ipsum decided to leave for the far World of Grammar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a last view back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of Alphabet Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane. Pityful a rethoric question ran over her cheek, then&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Name of the work 8</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fifth abundantly made Give sixth hath. Cattle creature i be don&amp;rsquo;t them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove right at the coast of the Semantics, a large language ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small river named Duden flows by their place and supplies it with the necessary regelialia. It is a paradisematic country, in which roasted parts of sentences fly into your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;header-level-2&#34;&gt;Header Level 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the all-powerful Pointing has no control about the blind texts it is an almost unorthographic life One day however a small line of blind text by the name of Lorem Ipsum decided to leave for the far World of Grammar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a last view back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of Alphabet Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane. Pityful a rethoric question ran over her cheek, then&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Item with image</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 20:02:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/portfolio/work9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and Consonantia, there live the blind texts. A small river named Duden flows by their place and supplies it with the necessary regelialia. It is a paradisematic country, in which roasted parts of sentences fly into your mouth.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove right at the coast of the Semantics, a large language ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small river named Duden flows by their place and supplies it with the necessary regelialia. It is a paradisematic country, in which roasted parts of sentences fly into your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;header-level-2&#34;&gt;Header Level 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the all-powerful Pointing has no control about the blind texts it is an almost unorthographic life One day however a small line of blind text by the name of Lorem Ipsum decided to leave for the far World of Grammar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn&amp;rsquo;t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliquam tincidunt mauris eu risus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a last view back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of Alphabet Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane. Pityful a rethoric question ran over her cheek, then&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>