<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Tyler Clavelle</title>
    <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Tyler Clavelle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2016 Tyler Clavelle</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Phish by the Numbers</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/phish_from_vt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/phish_from_vt/</guid>
      <description>“My geekiness is getting in the way of my nerdiness” - Patton Oswalt
 Phish is a quartet and stalwarts of the modern jam band scene they helped create in the late 80’s. Like their Deadhead contemporaries, Phish fans (phans) have an almost unhealthy obsession with the music, speaking in reverential tones of near mythical versions of songs, like 2015’s Tweezer -&amp;gt; Prince Caspian, while endlessly debating the details (for the record, no, I do not think they went back into Tweezer).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy citations in RMarkdown with RefManageR</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/reference_tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 18:39:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/reference_tips/</guid>
      <description>It’s Monday (or at least it was when I started writing this), so what better way to make the week’s most boring day even more boring than to write about citations? Managing and formatting references for your research is, well, about as fun as it sounds. Fortunately, gone are the days of manually curating these lists and cut/pasting your way to an alphabetical bibliography. In this post, I’ll demonstrate how to use the RefManageR package to manage your references and easily automate citations and bibliographies in RMarkdown documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Blog with Blogdown and GitHub</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/blogdown_github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 16:17:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/blogdown_github/</guid>
      <description>When I first started learning to code in R, Google was (and still is) my go-to when I had a question. It didn’t take long to realize that this generally brought me to one of two destinations - StackOverflow or [Insert Name]’s Blog. So, I created a StackOverflow account and decided to start my own data science blog. However, I didn’t quite know where to start and spent most of 2016 scoping different platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 18:32:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tclavelle.github.io/blog/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Well, I finally did it. I started a blog.
I have a variety of reasons for venturing into the blogosphere. First, I like to tell stories. Writing these stories down is a good exercise because, in verbal form, my stories have a tendency to meander off on unforeseen (though completely necessary) tangents. Second, blogs have become a go-to for me when seeking answers to my programming-related questions so I decided to start contributing to this resource base.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>